Rule Your Fate.
King Arthur is a adventure, war, history film directed by Antoine Fuqua.
The story of the Arthurian legend, based on the 'Sarmatian hypothesis' which contends that the legend has a historical nucleus in the Sarmatian heavy cavalry
troops stationed in Britain, and that the Roman-British military commander, Lucius Artorius Castus is the historical person behind the legend.
Arthur, played by Clive Owen.
Lancelot, played by Ioan Gruffudd.
Guinevere, played by Keira Knightley.
Tristan, played by Mads Mikkelsen.
Gawain, played by Joel Edgerton.
Galahad, played by Hugh Dancy.
King Arthur is a 2004 epic historical adventure film directed
by Antoine Fuqua and written by David Franzoni.
It features an ensemble cast with Clive Owen as the title character, Ioan Gruffudd as Lancelot and Keira Knightley as Guinevere, along with
Mads Mikkelsen, Joel Edgerton, Hugh Dancy, Ray Winstone, Ray Stevenson, Stephen Dillane, Stellan Skarsgård and Til Schweiger.
The film is unusual in reinterpreting Arthur as a Roman
officer rather than the typical medieval knight.
Several literary works have also done so, including David Gemmell's Ghost King, Jack Whyte's Camulod
Chronicles, and perhaps the strongest influence on this film, Bernard Cornwell's Warlord series.
The producers of the film attempted to market it as a more historically accurate version of
the Arthurian legends, supposedly inspired by new archaeological findings.
The film was shot in Ireland, England, and Wales.
King Arthur was released by Buena Vista Pictures through the
Touchstone Pictures label on 7 July 2004.
The film received mixed to negative reviews with critics criticizing the setting, violence and battle sequences while praising the musical
score, directing, performances and cinematography and grossed $203.6 million against a production budget of $120 million.
The film explores themes of roman empire, king
arthur, battle, 5th century, northumbria.
The tone is emotional.